Jinx Beers papers 1975-2013
UCLA Library Special Collections
Jinx Beers papers
1975-2013
2222
UCLA Library Special Collections
5 linear ft. (10 boxes)
Jinx Beers was founder of Lesbian News and lifelong lesbian activist throughout Southern California. This collection represents administrative activities of Lesbian News as well as the writing and publication of Beers's memoir and various stories and articles.
Beers, Jinx
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. STORED OFF-SITE AT SRLF. Advance notice is required for access to the collection. Please contact UCLA Library Special Collections for paging information.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 7400136
Acquisition Information
The materials were donated by Baylis Glascock.
This collection is part of an outreach and collection-building partnership between the June L. Mazer Lesbian Archives, the UCLA Center for the Study of Women (CSW) and the UCLA Library.
Biography
Jinx Beers was born in Pasadena, CA in 1933. She joined the Air Force and after receiving an honorable discharge, she remained active in Reserves for another twelve years. She resigned in 1974 due to the United States Military's policies concerning homosexuals. She then went on to earn a Bachelor of Arts degree from the University of California Los Angeles in experimental psychology. She worked at the UCLA Institute for Transportation and Traffic Engineering for eighteen years.
In 1973, Beers co-taught the first lesbian studies class at the Experimental College at the University of California Los Angeles, which served as a connecting point for many Los Angeles activists and yielded a group called Lesbian Activists.
In 1975, Beers founded The LN (The Lesbian News), a publication of lesbian news that is still active and published monthly. After fourteen years as the editor and owner of The LN, Jinx Beers sold the periodical and begin publishing LSF: Lesbian Short Fiction. She also managed the business of artist and partner Alicia Austin.
2008 saw the publication of her memoir, Memoirs of an Old Dyke and in 2009, she was honored with a proclamation by the City of West Hollywood as well as with an Etheridge Award for her service to the community.
Scope and Content
This collection includes Beers's personal materials including research and preparatory work for her memoir Memoirs of an Old Dyke as well as administrative materials for the magazine, Lesbian News.
Beers, Jinx -- Archives
Container List
- Lesbian News Correspondence., 1975-1976.; handwritten notes, envelopes (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Correspondence related to the operations and subscriptions of the Lesbian News.
- Lesbian News Correspondence., 1977.; handwritten notes, envelopes (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Lesbian News Correspondence., 1978.; handwritten notes, envelopes (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Lesbian News Correspondence., 1979.; handwritten notes, envelopes (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Lesbian News Correspondence., 1979-2005.; handwritten notes, envelopes (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Lesbian News Correspondence., 1980.; handwritten notes, envelopes (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Lesbian News Correspondence., 1982.; handwritten notes, envelopes (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Lesbian News Correspondence., 1983.; handwritten notes, envelopes (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Lesbian News Correspondence., 1984.; handwritten notes, envelopes (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Lesbian News Correspondence., 1985.; handwritten notes, envelopes (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Lesbian News - Correspondence., 1986.; handwritten notes, printed paper, envelopes (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Correspondence having to do with Lesbian News. Includes correspondence from advertisers, subscribers and readers.
- Lesbian News - Correspondence., 1987.; handwritten notes, printed paper, envelopes (Box 3, Folder 2)
  Correspondence having to do with the Lesbian News, includes correspondence from advertisers, subscribers and additional readers.
- Sale of the Lesbian News., July-August, 1989.; printed paper (Box 3, Folder 3)
  Includes agreements, correspondence, promissory notes, security agreement and bill of sale pertaining to the sale of the Lesbian News from Jinx Beers to Deborah Bergman.
- The Lesbian News., 1989-2005.; magazines, printed paper (Box 3, Folder 4)
  Includes four issues of The Lesbian News: September 1989, August 1997, February and April 2005.
- Non-fiction essays by Jinx Beers., 1960-1971.; printed paper with handwritten notes (Box 4, Folder 1)
  Includes: The Lesbian: Coworker, Wife and Mother That Western Sidewinder! Stop, Mother: Don't Deny Your Youngster a Pet Snake! Beauty Away from the Crowds: Lava Bed National Monument
- Short stories by Jinx Beers., 1990-2006.; printed paper with handwritten notes (Box 4, Folder 2)
  Includes: To Fly with Eagles No Turning Back Leonard The Election Everything is a Matter of Timing The Patchwork Dragon The Mouse The Best Laid Schemes The Amazing Miss Manody
- Jan (working title)., 1993.; printed paper (Box 4, Folder 3)
  Manuscript for Jan, a novella by Jinx Beers. Also includes correspondence with NAIAD Press.
- Poems., No Date.; printed paper (Box 4, Folder 4)
  Poems by Jinx Beers.
- Memoirs of an Old Dyke - Advertisements., 2009-2001.; printed paper (Box 4, Folder 5)
  Documents relating to advertising for Jinx Beers's memoirs.
- Memoirs of an Old Dyke - Review Information., 2010.; printed paper (Box 4, Folder 6)
  Copies of or notices of reviews of Memoirs of an Old Dyke.
- Radio Interview Information., 2010.; printed paper (Box 4, Folder 7)
  Emails, correspondence and other information concerning radio interviews with Jinx Beers.
- Book Orders., 2010.; printed paper (Box 4, Folder 8)
  Copies of orders for Memoirs of an Old Dyke.
- Miscellaneous., No Date.; printed paper (Box 4, Folder 9)
  Handwritten notes, copyright information and other research materials for self publishing.
- Promotional materials and correspondence., 2010-2011.; printed paper (Box 4, Folder 10)
  Correspondence with advertisers and promoters concerning Memoirs of an Old Dyke.
- Memoirs of an Old Dyke - Correction Process., 2008.; printed paper, handwritten notes (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Contains documentation of the correction process for Jinx Beers's memoir.
- Memoirs of an Old Dyke - Final Draft (submitted to publisher)., 2008.; printed paper (Box 5, Folder 2)
  Final draft of Jinx Beers's memoir, later submitted to publisher.
- Memoirs of an Old Dyke - Proof., 2009.; printed paper, photocopy (Box 5, Folder 3)
  A photocopied copy of the proof of Jinx Beers's memoir, includes visuals.
- Memoirs of an Old Dyke - Correspondence and Email., 2007-2009.; printed paper (Box 5, Folder 4)
  Correspondence, print outs of email concerning the publication, editing process and marketing of Jinx Beers's memoir.
- Memoirs of an Old Dyke - Photographs., No date.; photographs, photocopies (Box 5, Folder 5)
  Photographs used for Jinx Beers's memoir.
- Correspondence - Alicia Austin., 2004-2011.; printed paper, post it notes, handwritten notes (Box 6, Folder 1)
  Correspondence about the breakup of Alicia Austin and Jinx Beers. Includes correspondence between Alicia and Jinx as well as between friends in reference to the details and fallout of their breakup.
- Correspondence - Kathy, Gail and Alan., 2004-2013.; printed paper (Box 6, Folder 2)
  Correspondence between Jinx Beers and three friends, Kathy, Gail and Alan.
- Correspondence - Miscellaneous., 2005-2013.; printed paper (Box 6, Folder 3)
  Miscellaneous correspondence, both professional and personal of Jinx Beers.
- Correspondence - Awards/Interviews., 2008-2012.; printed paper (Box 6, Folder 4)
  Correspondence concerning the awards and interviews of Jinx Beers.
- Correspondence - Virginia., 2009-2011.; printed paper (Box 6, Folder 5)
  Correspondence between Jinx Beers and her friend Virginia.
- Rainbow Key Award Nomination Paperwork., 2010.; printed paper (Box 6, Folder 6)
  Paperwork for the nomination of the Rainbow Key Award, an award given by the city of West Hollywood, California for outstanding contributions to the gay and lesbian community.
- Correspondence - June L. Mazer Archives., 2010-2013.; printed paper (Box 6, Folder 7)
  Correspondence concerning the deposit of the Jinx Beers Papers to the June L. Mazer Archives.
- Correspondence - Professional., 2012.; printed paper (Box 6, Folder 8)
  Correspondence having to do with Jinx Beers's professional life.
- Volume Notes., 2013.; handwritten note (Box 6, Folder 9)
  Notes on volume assembled by Jinx Beers in preparation to donate her collection to the June L. Mazer Archives. Each folder has retained its original label.
- Photographs "Jinx as an Adult"., 1974-1999.; photographs (Box 7, Folder 1)
  Photographs from Jinx Beers's adult life.
- Photographs - "Jinx and/or Lovers"., 1975-2005.; photographs (Box 7, Folder 2)
  Photographs of Jinx with lovers over the years.
- FRONTIERS Magazine., 1985.; newsprint (Box 7, Folder 3)
  Jinx Beers was the cover story for this issue of FRONTIERS magazine.
- Ephemera/Awards., 1987-1995.; printed paper, ribbon (Box 7, Folder 4)
  Includes the Lesbian of the Year Award (homemade), Dick Michaels Media Awards and a Novel Writing Workshop Certificate.
- Handmade Cards., 2003-2005.; crosstiched paper (Box 7, Folder 5)
  Crosstitched homemade cards by Sister Virginia.
- Ransom Notes., 2005-2006.; printed paper (Box 7, Folder 6)
  Several issues of the "Ransom Notes"
- Handmade cards., 2006-2009.; crosstiched paper (Box 7, Folder 7)
  Crosstiched homemade cards by Sister Virginia.
- Nobody Loves you Like a Sister., 2007.; bound book (Box 7, Folder 8)
  Published book through New Leaf Press.
- Handmade Cards., 2010-2011.; crosstiched paper (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Photographs - "Airforce/Germany"., No date.; photographs (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Photographs - "Jinx as child"., No date.; Photographs (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Photographs - Miscellaneous., No date.; photographs (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Photos and photo discs., No date.; photographs and CD-Rs (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Ephemera., 1980-2002.; frames, paper, plaques (Box 8)
  Contains framed personal notes as well as three diplomas: CCC Management Team Recognizes Jinx Beers for United States Military Service on Veteran's Day 2002 Certificate of Achievement from the Los Angeles Department of Water and Power for completing a course in Basic Customer Service Procedures 1999 Bachelor of Arts Diploma with a Major in Psychology from the University of California 1963 CCC Star Hitter for Perfect Attendance 2004
- Ephemera., No date.; softball mitt, quilt, plaques (Box 9)
- Ephemera., No date.; photographs, patches (Box 10)